{
  "cards": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Q: What is the supreme law of the land?",
      "answer": "A: The Constitution"
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Q: What does the Constitution do?",
    "answer": "A: (1) sets up the government (2) defines the government (3) protects basic rights of Americans"
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Q: The idea of self-government is in the first three words of the Constitution. What are these words?",
    "answer": "A: We the people"
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Q: What is an amendment?",
    "answer": "A: a change/addition to the Constitution"
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Q: What do we call the first ten amendments to the Constitution?",
    "answer": "A: Bill of Rights"
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Q: What is one right or freedom from the First Amendment?",
    "answer": "A: speech, religion, assembly, press, petition the government"
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Q: How many amendments does the Constitution have?",
    "answer": "A: 27"
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Q: What did the Declaration of Independence do?",
    "answer": "A: announced/declared our independence from Great Britain"
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Q: What are 2 rights in the Declaration of Independence?",
    "answer": "A: life, liberty, pursuit of happiness"
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Q: What is freedom of religion?",
    "answer": "A: The freedom to practice any religion, or to not practice a religion"
    },
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Q: What is the economic system in the United States?",
    "answer": "A: capitalist economy; market economy"
    },
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Q: What is the 'rule of the law?'",
    "answer": "A: Everyone must follow the law, leaders & the government must obey the law; no one is above the low"
    },
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Q: Name one branch or part of the government.",
    "answer": "A: Congress, legislative, President, executive, the courts, judicial"
    },
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Q: What stops one branch of government from becoming too powerful?",
    "answer": "A: checks and balances, separation of powers"
    },
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Q: Who is in charge of the executive branch?",
    "answer": "A: the President"
    },
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Q: Who makes federal laws?",
    "answer": "A: Congress, Senate and House (of Representatives), (US or National) legislature"
    },
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Q: What are the two parts of the US Congress?",
    "answer": "A: The Senate and House (of Representatives)"
    },
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Q: How many US Senators are there?",
    "answer": "A: 100"
    },
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Q: We elect a US Senator for how many years?",
    "answer": "A: Six years"
    },
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Q: Who is one of your state's US Senators now?",
    "answer": "A: Marco Rubio"
    },
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Q: The House of Representatives has how many voting members?",
    "answer": "A: 435"
    },
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Q: We elect a US Representative for how many years?",
    "answer": "A: 2 years"
    },
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Q: Name your US Representative.",
    "answer": "A: List of Florida representatives can be found here:",
    "link": "https://www.govtrack.us/congress/members/FL#representatives"
    },
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Q: Who does a US Senator represent?",
    "answer": "A: all people of the state"
    },
    {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Q: Why do some states have more Representatives than other states?",
    "answer": "A: Because some states have more people"
    },
    {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Q: We elect a President for how many years?",
    "answer": "A: 4 years"
    },
    {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Q: In what month do we vote for the President?",
    "answer": "A: November"
    },
    {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Q: Who is the current President of the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Donald Trump"
    },
    {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Q: Who is the current Vice President of the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Mike Pence"
    },
    {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Q: If the President can no longer serve, who becomes President?",
    "answer": "A: the Vice President"
    },
    {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Q: If both the President and the Vice President can no longer serve, who becomes President?",
    "answer": "A: Speaker of the House (Paul Ryan)"
    },
    {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Q: Who is the Commander in Chief of the military?",
    "answer": "A: the President"
    },
    {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Q: Who signs bills to become laws?",
    "answer": "A: the President"
    },
    {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Q: Who vetoes bills?",
    "answer": "A: the President"
    },
    {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Q: What does the President's Cabinet do?",
    "answer": "A: advises the President"
    },
    {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Q: What are two Cabinet-level positions?",
    "answer": "A: Secretary of Education, Secretary of the Treasury, VP, Secretary of Energy"
    },
    {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Q: What does the Judicial branch do?",
    "answer": "A: reviews laws, explains laws, resolves disputed and decides if a law goes against the Constitution"
    },
    {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Q: What is the highest court in the United States?",
    "answer": "A: the Supreme Court"
    },
    {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Q: How many justices are on the Supreme Court?",
    "answer": "A: nine (9)"
    },
    {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Q: Who is the Chief of Justice of the United States now?",
    "answer": "A: John Roberts"
    },
    {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "Q: Under our Constitution, some powers belong to the Federal Government. What is one power of the Federal Government?",
    "answer": "A: to print money, to declare ware, to create an army and to make treaties"
    },
    {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Q: Under our Constitution, some powers belong to the states. What is one power of the states?",
    "answer": "A: provide schooling and education, provide protection, safety, give a driver's license, approve zoning and land use"
    },
    {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Q: Who is the Governor of your state now?",
    "answer": "A: Rick Scott (R)"
    },
    {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Q: What is the capital of your state?",
    "answer": "A: Rick Scott (R)"
    },
    {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Q: What are the 2 major political parties in the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Democratic and Republican"
    },
    {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Q: What is the political party of the President now?",
    "answer": "A: Republican"
    },
    {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Q: What is the name of the Speaker of the House of Representatives now?",
    "answer": "A: Paul Ryan"
    },
    {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Q: There are four amendments to the Constitution about who can vote. Describe one of them.",
    "answer": "A: Citizens 18 and older can vote; any citizen can vote"
    },
    {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "Q: What is one responsibility that is only for United States citizens?",
    "answer": "A: serve on a jury; vote in a federal election"
    },
    {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Q: Name one right only for United States citizens.",
    "answer": "A: vote in a federal election; run for federal office"
    },
    {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "Q: What are two rights of everyone living in the United States?",
    "answer": "A: freedom of speech, religion, expression; the right to bear arms"
    },
    {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "Q: What do we show loyalty to when we say the Pledge of Allegiance?",
    "answer": "A: the United States, the flag"
    },
    {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "Q: What is one promise you make when you become a United States Citizen?",
    "answer": "A: give up loyalty to other countries, defend the Constitution and laws of the United States"
    },
    {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "Q: How old do citizens have to be to vote for President?",
    "answer": "A: >= 18 years"
    },
    {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "Q: What are two ways that Americans can participate in their democracy?",
    "answer": "A: vote, join a political party, publicly support or oppose an issue or policy"
    },
    {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "Q: When is the last day you can send in federal income tax forms?",
    "answer": "A: April 15"
    },
    {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Q: When must all men register for the Selective Service?",
    "answer": "A: at age 18; between 18 and 26"
    },
    {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "Q: What is one reason colonists came to America?",
    "answer": "A: freedom, political liberty, religious freedom, escape persecution"
    },
    {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Q: Who lived in America before the Europeans arrived?",
    "answer": "A: American Indians"
    },
    {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "Q: What group of people was taken to America and sold as slaves?",
    "answer": "A: Africans"
    },
    {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "Q: Why did colonists fight the British?",
    "answer": "A: Because of high taxes, because the British army stayed in THEIR houses, and because they didn't have self-government"
    },
    {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "Q: Who wrote the Declaration of Independence?",
    "answer": "A: Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "Q: When was the Declaration of Independence adopted?",
    "answer": "A: July 4, 1776"
    },
    {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "Q: There were 13 original states. Name three.",
    "answer": "A: Georgia, North Carolina, New York,"
    },
    {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Q: What happened at the Constitutional Convention?",
    "answer": "A: The Constitution was written; The Founding Fathers wrote the Constitution"
    },
    {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "Q: When was the Constitution written?",
    "answer": "A: 1787"
    },
    {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "Q: The Federalist Papers supported the passage of the US Constitution. Name one of the writers.",
    "answer": "A: James Madison, Alexander Hamilton"
    },
    {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Q: What is one thing Benjamin Franklin is famous for?",
    "answer": "A: US Diplomat, oldest member of the Constitutional Convention, started the first free libraries"
    },
    {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "Q: Who is the 'Father of our Country'?",
    "answer": "A: George Washington"
    },
    {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "Q: Who was the first President?",
    "answer": "A: George Washington"
    },
    {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "Q: What territory did the US buy from France in 1803?",
    "answer": "A: Louisiana"
    },
    {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "Q: Name one war fought by the US in the 1800s.",
    "answer": "A: Civil War"
    },
    {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Q: Name the US war between the North and the South.",
    "answer": "A: the Civil War"
    },
    {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "Q: Name one problem that led to the Civil War.",
    "answer": "A: slavery, economic reasons, states' rights"
    },
    {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "Q: What was one important thing that Abraham Lincoln did?",
    "answer": "A: freed the slaves (Emancipation Proclamation), saved/preserved the Union, led the US during the Civil War"
    },
    {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "Q: What did the Emancipation Proclamation do?",
    "answer": "A: freed the slaves in the Confederate States"
    },
    {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Q: What did Susan B. Anthony do?",
    "answer": "A: fought for women's rights; fought for civil rights"
    },
    {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Q: Name one war fought by the US in the 1900s.",
    "answer": "A: WW I, WW II, Korean War, Vietnam War, (Persian) Gulf War"
    },
    {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "Q: Who was the President during World War I?",
    "answer": "A: Woodrow Wilson"
    },
    {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Q: Who was the President during the Great Depression and World War II?",
    "answer": "A: Franklin Roosevelt"
    },
    {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "Q: Who did the US fight in WW II?",
    "answer": "A: Japan, Germany and Italy"
    },
    {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Q: Before he was President, Eisenhower was a general. What war was he in?",
    "answer": "A: WW II"
    },
    {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "Q: During the Cold War, what was the main concern of the US?",
    "answer": "A: Communism"
    },
    {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "Q: What movement tried to end racial discrimination?",
    "answer": "A: Civil Rights Movement"
    },
    {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "Q: What did Martin Luther King, Jr. do?",
    "answer": "A: Fought for civil rights, worked for equality for all Americans"
    },
    {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "Q: What major event happened on September 11, 2001, in the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Terrorists attacked the US"
    },
    {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "Q: Name one American Indian tribe in the US.?",
    "answer": "A: Seminole Tribe"
    },
    {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Q: Name one of the two longest rivers in the US.",
    "answer": "A: Mississippi River"
    },
    {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "Q: What ocean is on the west coast of the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "Q: What ocean is on the east coast of the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Q: Name one US territory.",
    "answer": "A: Puerto Rico"
    },
    {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "Q: Name one state that borders Canada.",
    "answer": "A: Michigan, Ohio, New York"
    },
    {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "Q: Name one state that borders Mexico.",
    "answer": "A: Texas, Arizona, California, New Mexico"
    },
    {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "Q: What is the capital of the United States?",
    "answer": "A: Washington, D.C."
    },
    {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "Q: Where is the Statue of Liberty?",
    "answer": "A: New York; Liberty Island, Hudson River"
    },
    {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Q: Why does the flag have 13 stripes?",
    "answer": "A: because there were 13 original colonies"
    },
    {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Q: Why does the flag have 50 stars?",
    "answer": "A: to represent the 50 states"
    },
    {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "Q: What is the name of the national anthem?",
    "answer": "A: The Star-Spangled Banner"
    },
    {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "Q: When do we celebrate Independence Day?",
    "answer": "A: July 4"
    },
    {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "Q: Name 2 national US holidays.",
    "answer": "A: Independence Day, President's Day, Veteran's Day, Thanksgiving"
    }
  ]
}